宝贝
Hey, babe.
我们就要去度蜜月了  你期待吗
Aren't you excited we're going on our honeymoon?
我很期待
Yeah, I am.
百慕大  巴哈马  来吧  漂亮姑娘
Bermuda, Bahama, come on pretty mama.
没错  要发作就趁现在没人的时候
That's right, get it out of your system while we're alone.
我们是来送别的
Hey. We came to say goodbye.
对  祝你们蜜月玩得愉快
Yeah. Have a great honeymoon.
谢谢  我最好去打包行李
Thanks.  I better go pack.
不  我已经打好包了
No, I already packed.
我只是找不到你的迷你泳裤了
The only thing I couldn't find, though, was your Speedo.
我没有迷你泳裤
Speedo? I don't have a Speedo.
我要去打包我那条普通的超长泳裤
I'm gonna go pack my regular, long bathing suit.
很好  你还在
Good, you're still here!
我想来祝你有个愉快的蜜月
I wanted to tell you to have a good honeymoon.
谢谢
Thank you!
我还要你们知道
And I also wanted you guys to know that
今天我会告诉孩子他爸
I am telling the father today.
怎么了
What? What? What?
我们知道孩子他爸是罗斯
We know it's Ross.
你怎么知道的
How? How do you know?
那是他的毛衣  我们都又惊又喜
It was his sweater. But, oh, my God!
我好希望罗斯是第一个知道的
I so wanted Ross to know first.
但你们知道了  我真的松了一口气
But I am so relieved that you guys know!
这真的是太棒了
That is so great.
我要当姑姑了  我知道
And I'm gonna be your baby's aunt!  I know.
我要当阿姨了
Me too!
我要当叔叔了  来吧
And I'm gonna be an uncle! Come here.
你们要当孩子的姑姑  阿姨跟叔叔了
You're all gonna be aunts and uncles.
对  但只有我跟孩子有血缘关系
Yeah, but I'm the only one related by blood.
现在你们知道了  你们可以帮我
Great! So now that you all know, you can help me.
建议我该怎么跟罗斯说
Give me some advice on how to I'm gonna tell Ross.
你打算怎么说
What were you gonna say?
我要告诉他我想留下孩子
I was gonna tell him that I'm gonna have the baby,
他想怎么做都可以
and he can be as involved as he wants.
听起来很不错
Well, that sounds good.
对  但我该怎么开口呢
Yeah, but, you know, how do I start?
我是说我的开场白应该是什么
I mean, what's the first thing that I say?
好吧  太棒了  谢谢
Okay, great. Thanks.
祝你好运   再见
Hey, good luck.  Yeah, bye.
刚才是怎么一回事
Hey, what was that all about?
看来现在告诉你也没关系了
Well, I guess there's no harm in telling you now.
瑞秋怀了罗斯的孩子
Rachel and Ross are going to have a baby.
什么
What?!
我完全不知道  你为什么不告诉我
I didn't even know that...!Why didn't you tell me?
我为什么会这用这种声音说话
Why am I talking like this?
我觉得你藏不住秘密
I didn't think you could keep it a secret.
什么
What?!
我的嘴可严了
I am an excellent secretkeeper.
我一直保守着我们所有的秘密
I have kept all our secrets.
什么秘密  不  乔伊
What secrets?  No, no, Joey.
我不会告诉你  因为我的嘴很严
I'm not gonna tell you, because I am an excellent secretkeeper.
待会你会告诉我  你已经知道了
You'll tell me later?  You already know.
《老友记》  第八季  第3集  瑞秋告诉了罗斯
Friends S08E03 The One Where Rachel Tells…
送别人去度蜜月  真的好浪漫
It's so romantic to send people off on their honeymoon.
莫妮卡跟钱德勒结婚了
You know, Monica and Chandler are married.
罗斯跟瑞秋就要生宝宝了
Ross and Rachel are having a baby.
或许你跟我也该找些事来做
Maybe you and I should do something.
别急  吾爱  等到合适的时机吧
All in good time, my love. All in good time.
该死  我把吉他放在他们家了
Shoot! I left my guitar in their apartment.
你待会能帮我开门吧
Well, you can let me in later, right?
不行  我没有钥匙
No, I don't have a key.
他们拿走我的钥匙说是要交给你
They took mine to give to you.
什么  他们拿走我的说是要交给你
What? They took mine to give to you.
他们为什么要拿走我们的钥匙
Why would they take away our keys?
或许他们不信任我们
Maybe they don't trust us.
不对啊  他们上次出城时
That's not it. They let me keep my key
还让我帮他们保管钥匙
the last time they were out of town.
那次你打破番茄酱瓶
You mean the time you broke the ketchup bottle
拿莫妮卡给客人准备的毛巾来清理
and cleaned it with Monica's guest towels?
我洗了毛巾  才没有
Hey, I washed those.  No, you didn't.
对  那听起来不像我的作风
Yeah, that didn't sound like me.
我该怎么办  我真的要用吉他
What am I gonna do? I really need my guitar.
我也有东西放在他们家
I have stuff in there too.
什么东西  莫妮卡的奶酪鸡排
What stuff?  Monica's chicken parm.
我来想办法解决
I'll take care of it.
崔格先生  我是乔伊·崔比安尼
Hey, Mr. Treeger? It's Joey Tribbiani.
听着  我得去莫妮卡跟钱德勒家
Listen, I need to get into Monica and Chandler's apartment.
有紧急事件
It's an emergency!
煤气泄漏  带大蒜面包过来
Gas leak. Oh, and bring garlic bread.
瑞秋找到你了吗  没有  怎么了
Did Rachel find you?  No, why?
她在找你
She was looking for you.
那我待会再见她
Well, I guess I'll catch up with her later.
她真的得马上跟你谈
She really wanted to talk to you now.
对  似乎是有重要的事
Yeah, it seemed pretty important.
不
Oh, no.
怎么
What?
我想我知道她要跟我谈什么了
I think I might know what this is about.
真的吗
Really?
对
Yeah.
我们答应不会告诉任何人  但是...
We promised we weren't gonna tell anybody this, but...
大约一个月前瑞秋跟我上床了
About a month ago, Rachel and I slept together.
结果呢
And?
我以为你们会大吃一惊
Wow, I thought you'd be a little more shocked.
抱歉  结果呢
Oh, sorry. And?!
我们说只做一次...
Well, we said we'd just do it that one time...
我想她现在或许想要跟我复合
...but now I think she may wanna start things up again.
我想不是那样的
Yeah, I don't think that's what it is.
怎么  不然会是什么事
Why? What else could it be?
我觉得不太舒服
Oh, wow, I don't feel well.
我觉得就是那么一回事
I'm telling you, I'm telling you, that's what it is.
难怪在婚礼上  她看我的眼神怪怪的
No wonder she was looking at me all funny during the wedding.
她什么都没有告诉你们吗
She didn't say anything to you?
或许你吃错东西了  有可能
Maybe it's something you ate.  Could be, yeah.
拜托  去跟瑞秋谈一谈  好吧
Please, just go and talk to Rachel.  Yeah, I guess I should.
你们知道我领悟到什么事吗
Man, you know what I have to realize?
或许我是那种让女人一夜难忘的男人
Maybe I'm not the type of guy women can have just one night with.
她们对我永远都觉得不满足
You know, they always seem to want a little bit more.
我应该记住那一点
I should remember that.
下一位
Next.
他们在接吻  我们先过去吧
They're kissing. Let's just go around them.
别打扰他们  他们深爱彼此
Honey, leave them alone. They're in love.
我也爱你  不过爱得井然有序
I'm in love too. But in an orderly fashion.
下一位
Next.
你们能边走边接吻吗
Hi. Can you do that and walk?
她说"下一位"了
Because she said, "Next."
抱歉  我们没有听到
Sorry, we didn't hear you.
我们要去度蜜月
We're on our honeymoon.
让我来看一下
Let me see what I can do.
头等舱还有位置
There are some firstclass seats available.
你听到没有
Did you hear that?
她让他们升级到头等舱
They bumped them up to first class
因为他们要去度蜜月
because they're on their honeymoon!
我们假装也要去度蜜月
Come on. Let's act like we're on our honeymoon.
我们的确是要去度蜜月
We are on our honeymoon.
快摸我屁股
Grab my ass.
下一位  抱歉  我差点没听见
Next.  Hi. Sorry, I almost didn't hear you,
我深爱我的新婚丈夫
because, you know, I'm just so in love with my new husband.
我们要去度蜜月
We're on our honeymoon.
恭喜  谢谢
Congratulations.  Thanks.
好了  宾先生  你在25J
Okay, Mr. Bing, you'll be in 25J,
宾太太是25K
and Mrs. Bing, you're in 25K.
我们要去度蜜月
We're on our honeymoon,
你能让我们升级到头等舱吗
so can you do your little thing and bump us to first class?
抱歉  头等舱客满了
I'm sorry, all the firstclass seats are taken.
刚刚那对夫妻拿走最后两个位置
That couple got the last two.
看吧  如果你听我的话  插他们的队
See? If we'd gone around them like I said,
她会给我们头等舱的位置  该死
she'd have given us those tickets! Damn it!
25J跟K会不会刚好不连在一起
25J and K, any chance those aren't together?
我还是不敢相信他们拿走了我的钥匙
I still can't believe they took away my key.
你都把你的钥匙交给我保管
I mean, you trust me with yours.
那当然  等清理钥匙的人把它擦干挣之后
Of course I do! And I'm gonna get it back to you just as soon as
我就会还给你
they're done with it at the keyshining place.
那是什么声音  我不知道
What the hell is that?  I don't know.
崔格  你在做什么
Treeger, what are you doing?
你说有煤气泄漏
You said there was a gas leak in here.
你为什么不用钥匙开门
Why not use your key?
等我找到他们家的钥匙
Because by the time I found it on this thing,
这间公寓可能都炸掉了
the whole place might have exploded.
如果我管理的公寓再发生一次爆炸意外
If that happens at another building I manage,
人们会开始问问题
people will ask questions.
快一点
Come on, hurry up!
要那么做我们也会
Well, we could have done that.
你看  他们走进头等舱休息室了
Look at that! They're going into the firstclass lounge.
你知道里面有什么吗  不知道
Do you know what they have in there?  No.
我也不知道  我们得进去才行
Me neither. We have to get in!
装做你是头等舱的客人  天啊  有橘子
Just act like you belong.  Oh, my God! Oranges!
很高兴又跟你见面了
Nice to see you again.
先生  麻烦出示你的机票
Sir, may I see your tickets, please?
没问题
Yes, of course.
抱歉  麻烦将你的姆指挪开
I'm sorry. Would you move your thumb?
我看不到座位号码
I can't see the seat number.
没关系  我已经背下来了  是1A
That's all right. I have it memorized. It's 1 A.
这不是头等舱的机票  抱歉
Sir, this isn't a firstclass ticket. I'm sorry.
没关系  不好意思
Apology accepted. Excuse us.
先生  恐怕我得请你们离开
Sir, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
好吧
Fine.
快跑
Go, go, go!
我想我们真的需要好好谈一谈
I think there's something that we really need to talk about.
没错  我们先进去吧
I think we do. Why don't we go inside.
我知道你为什么会来找我  真的吗
Look, I know why you're here.  You do?
对  为了让你别太尴尬
Yeah, and to save you from any embarrassment...
我想或许应该我先说
...I think maybe I should talk first.
好吧  好吗
Okay.  Okay?
罗斯跟瑞秋
Ross and Rachel.
瑞秋跟罗斯
Rachel and Ross.
很像是在玩跷跷板  对吧
That's been one heck of a seesaw, hasn't it?
什么
What?
我是说那晚
I mean, look, that one night
我们过得既满足又尽性
we had was fun and certainly passionate.
但你不觉得我们还是当朋友比较好吗
But don't you think it's better if we just stay friends?
你是说...什么
Seriously, what?
好吧  这样好了
Okay, okay. You know what?
如果你想的话  我们可以再做一次
If you want to, we can do it one more time.
我没有问题
I mean, I'd be okay with that.
事实上我现在有空
In fact, I have some time right now...
好了
Okay.
你知道吗  我可以说话了吗
You know what? Can I talk now?
当然可以 好吧
Oh, sure.  Okay.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
罗斯
Ross?
好吧  我等你准备好再说
Okay, whenever you're ready.
对了  你是孩子他爸  你继续
And you're the father, by the way. But you got...
你要喝水吗  我没事
Can I get you some water?  I'm good. I'm good.
罗斯  别觉得有什么压力  好吗
Ross, there is no pressure on you, okay?
你想怎么做都可以的
I mean, you can be as involved as you want.
对  我...
Yeah, I...
我只是不知道... 我不明白...
I'm just, I don't know. I don't understand...
怎么会发生这种事
...how this happened.
我们有用安全套  我知道
We used a condom.  I know.
但安全套的避孕率只有97%
But you know, condoms only work, like, 97 percent of the time.
什么
What?
What?!
他们应该标示在包装上
Well, they should put that on the box!
包装上有标示  才没有
They do.  No, they don't!
他们应该用又大又粗的字体标示在包装上
Well, they should put it in huge block letters!
罗斯  别管安全套的事
Ross, let's just forget about the condoms.
早知道当时也不用管了
Well, I may as well have!
你知道吗  我发现自己怀孕时...
Listen, you know what? I was really freaked out too...
也吓坏了  吓坏了  我才没有
...when I found out.  Freaked...?Hey, I'm not freaked out.
作为消费者  我很愤怒
I'm indignant as a consumer!
你知道吗  我们待会再谈
You know what? Let's talk later.
不  我想现在谈
No, I wanna talk now.
事实上我想...
In fact, I wanna talk...
跟安全套公司的总裁谈
...to the president of the condom company.
或许我该待会再来  好吧
Okay, you know what? Maybe I should come back... Okay.
好吧  我按一
Yeah, I'll press one!
我到处都检查过  没有煤气泄漏
I looked everywhere. There's no gas leak.
我可以热一下这个吗
So then I can heat this up?
总之我会帮他装扇新门
Anyway, I'll get moving on that new door.
太棒了  你能帮我们一个忙
Great. Listen, could you do us a favor
别跟钱德勒和莫妮卡提这件事吗
and not tell Chandler and Monica about this?
因为他们没有自己的孩子...
Because, you know, they don't have any kids of their own...
这扇门就像是他们的孩子
...and this door was like a child to them.
我得装上新锁
Well, I'm gonna have to put on a new lock.
他们一定会发现的
They'll find out anyway.
不是吧
Oh, no.
看样子要干一整天
It's looking like an allday job.
我得去取消我的瑜伽课
I'm gonna have to cancel my yoga class.
罗斯  麻烦你告诉茉莉
Hey, Ross. Could you tell Jasmine
今天我没办法去上瑜伽课  没问题
I can't make it to yoga class today?  Sure.
再见  再见
Namaste.  Namaste.
天啊  门是怎么了
Oh, my God! What happened to the door?
看来很明显
So it's noticeable, huh?
瑞秋在这里吗  我得跟她谈一谈
Look, is Rachel here? I need to talk to her.
你们不是谈过了吗
Didn't you two already talk?
对  但是
Yeah, but...
听着  你们知道  瑞秋跟我上过床
Okay. Look, you guys know that Rachel and I slept together...
但除此之外还有别的事
...but there's something else.
瑞秋怀孕了
Rachel's pregnant.
我的老天爷  天啊  我不敢相信
Holy mother of God!  Oh, my God, I can't believe that!
她怀了我的孩子  我是第一次听到这件事
With my child.  That is brandnew information!
你们已经知道了对不对  知道一点
You already know, don't you?  Little bit.
你还好吗  我会没事的
How you doing?  Okay. I mean, I'll be okay.
我觉得自己处理得不够好
It's just, I don't think I handled it very well.
你跟她说了什么  什么都没说
What'd you say to her?  Nothing.
但我跟安全套公司的客服部门倒是说了不少
But the complaint department at the condom company got an earful.
我一转身才发现她走了  罗斯
Then when I turned around, she was gone.  Oh, Ross.
我知道  但我刚刚才发现
I know. But in my defense,
安全套只有97%的避孕率
I just found out that condoms are only, like, 97% effective.
什么  我得去找她
What?  I gotta go find her.
等一下  你是认真的吗
Hey. Hold on! Are you serious?
所以安全套有3%的机率不起作用
So, like, 3 percent of the time, they don't even work?
他们应该在包装上做标示
They should put that on the box!
他们的确做了标示  什么
Evidently, they do.  What?!
我不敢相信我们到这里了
I can't believe we're here.
开什么玩笑  怎么
You've gotta be kidding.  What?
为了庆祝你们新婚
As a wedding gift to you,
酒店要帮你们升级到蜜月套房
the hotel would like to give you the honeymoon suite.
不  你们一整天都跟我们过不去
No! You have been screwing us all day!
你们是谁  我们就是你们
Who are you?  We're you.
只是迟了十秒钟
Just 10 seconds later!
你们已经抢走头等舱的位置和休息室
You already got the firstclass tickets, you got the lounge.
我们也应该得到免费招待
We should get free stuff too!
不光是你们在度蜜月
You're not the only ones on your honeymoon!
我们可以把蜜月套房让给你们
You can have the suite if you want.
我们不在乎要睡在哪里
We don't care about where we stay.
我们来这里纪念我们对彼此的爱
We're here to celebrate our love for each other.
我们不需要免费招待
We don't have to get free stuff.
我们只想在一起
We just want to be together.
我们需要免费招待
We need the stuff.
莫妮卡  我是乔伊
Monica, it's Joey. Listen.
菲比跟我闻到你家有煤气味
Phoebe and I smell gas coming from your apartment.
什么  真的吗  乔伊闻到有煤气味
What? Are you serious? Joey smells gas.
还有什么新消息
What else is new?
我们想进去看看  但你拿走了我们的钥匙
We'd check it out, but you took our keys.
快想办法进去
Well, do something. Get in there!
要怎么办呢  我可以把你家大门撞开
How? I guess I could break down your door.
对  就那么做
Yeah, do that.
你不会怪我们弄坏东西  不会
And you won't blame us for any damage?  No.
你在撞门了吗  我没有听到声音  快呀
Are you doing it? I don't hear anything. Come on.
好吧  我来撞门了
Okay, I'll break it down.
他正在撞门  他要把门撞开了
Hi. He's doing it, he's breaking down the door.
好了  我们进来了
Okay, we're in.
瑞秋  你感觉舒服吗
Okay, Rachel, are you comfortable?
如果我说很舒服  你会另眼看我吗
If I said I was, would you judge me?
医生马上过来帮你照超声波
The doctor'll be here in a minute to do your sonogram.
好的
Okay.
天啊  我发誓  如果他们在家具店卖这个
Oh, man, I swear, if they sold these at Pottery Barn...
我们得谈一谈
We need to talk.
现在吗  我现在的姿势有点不雅
Right now? Because I kind of got an alfresco situation going on over here.
拜托  我真的...
Please, I really...
我想为我刚刚的表现向你道歉
I want to apologize for the way I acted earlier today.
没关系  麻烦你待在床头边
Okay, Ross. That's fine. Can you stay up near my head?
什么  抱歉
What? Oh, yeah, sorry.
我被冲昏头了  我只想到自己
I think I went a little crazy. I was thinking about myself
我应该要为你着想
when I should've been thinking about you...
没关系  待在床头这边  罗斯  好
Okay, head, Ross! Head, Ross!  Right.
我要你知道
I want you to know that
我会一直陪在你身边  好吗
I'm gonna be there through this whole thing. Okay?
来做产检  上拉梅兹呼吸课
The doctor's appointments, the Lamaze classes,
在公寓里为宝宝安装保护措施
babyproofing the apartment.
但我们可以等到婚后再担心那些事
Although, we can worry about that after we get married.
婚后  对  我想我们应该结婚
Married?  Well, yeah, I think we should get married.
你一遇到问题就用结婚来解决吗
Because that's your answer to everything?
不  那么做是对的
No. Because that's the right thing to do.
或许吧  只要我们相爱
Yeah, maybe, if you're in love.
可是罗斯  我们并不相爱  对吧
But Ross, we are not in love, are we?
对  但是你不可能一个人处理这件事
No. But still, I mean, you can't possibly do this alone.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你甚至没办法一个人在餐厅吃饭
Come on, Rach. You can't even eat alone in a restaurant.
什么  如果你没办法一个人吃饭
What?  I'm just saying if you can't eat by yourself,
你怎么一个人带孩子
how do you expect to have a baby by yourself?
我可以一个人吃饭
I can too eat by myself!
你什么时候一个人吃过
When have you ever?
当某些同桌的人吃完饭
When certain people leave the table
我还没有吃完的时候
and I am not finished!
有些人光喝一碗汤就得花掉两个小时
Well, certain other people take two hours to eat a bowl of soup!
拜托  是你狼吞虎咽
Oh, please. You inale your food.
我跟莫妮卡一起长大
I grew up with Monica.
不吃快一点的话就没得吃了
If you didn't eat fast, you didn't eat!
我打扰你们了吗
Am I interrupting?
不  朗格医生  请进
No, Dr. Long. Please come in.
他是罗斯  孩子的爸爸
This is Ross. He is the father.
但我不是她的丈夫  因为显然她能单独带大孩子
But not the husband, because, evidently, she can do this alone.
很高兴能见到你  我要开始检查了
Nice to meet you. I'll get started on this.
你为什么不能承认你需要我
I don't know why you can't admit you need me?
我的确需要你  我需要你站在床头这边
I do need you. I need you to stay near my head!
好吧  看起来很正常
Okay. Everything looks good.
银幕上的画面是这样的
Here it is on the screen.
这是你的子宫...
Here's your uterus...
宝宝在这里
...and right here is your baby.
天啊
Oh, my God.
它在那里  我看到了
There it is. I see it.
恭喜  我让你们独处一下
Congratulations. I'll give you two a minute.
好吧  谢谢
Okay.  Thank you.
很神奇吧
Pretty amazing, huh?
我看不到
I don't see it!
什么  我看不到
What? What?  I can't see it.
但你说你看到了
But you just said that you did.
我知道  我说谎了
I know. I lied.
我不希望她认为我是个很糟糕的母亲
I didn't want her to think I was a terrible mother.
我连自己的宝宝都看不到
I can't even see my own baby!
过来  你可以看到的
Oh, sure. Come here. Sure, you can.
过来  就在这里
Come here. Look, it's right there.
好漂亮
Oh, it's beautiful.
我看到了
I see it now.
真的吗  不  我看不到
Do you really?  No, I don't see it!
好吧  来吧
Okay. Come on. All right. Okay.
你看到那个像花生一样的小东西了吗
You see this tiny thing that looks like a peanut?
是的
Yeah.
亲爱的  就是那个
Sweetie, that's it.
就是那个
That's it?
我看到了
Well, I saw that.
谢谢  别客气
Thank you.  You're welcome.
我不敢相信那是我们的孩子
Wow, I can't believe that's our baby.
对  那是我们的孩子
Yeah, that's our baby.
医生怎么说
So how was the doctor?
一切都很顺利
Everything went great.
很好  让他们看看你子宫的照片
Good.  Hey, show them the picture of your uterus.
我看不到宝宝  它在哪里
I don't see the baby. Where is it?
我知道  刚开始我也看不到
Oh, no, I know. I couldn't see it either at first.
但它就在...
But it's right...
罗斯  我又看不到了
Ross, I lost it again.